<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>AWS的一些笔记</title>
    <link href="/2024/05/03/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/"/>
    <url>/2024/05/03/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Note"><a href="#Note" class="headerlink" title="Note"></a>Note</h2><p><strong>Support Plan</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224111535733.png" alt="image-20240224111535733"></p><p><strong>Compute</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224112604274.png" alt="image-20240224112604274"></p><p><strong>Network</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224112826127.png" alt="image-20240224112826127"></p><p><strong>Database</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113049307.png" alt="image-20240224113049307"></p><p><strong>Provisioning</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113300080.png" alt="image-20240224113300080"></p><p><strong>Storage</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113420783.png" alt="image-20240224113420783"></p><p><strong>Business Centric Service</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113600488.png" alt="image-20240224113600488"></p><p><strong>Enterprise Integration</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113754298.png" alt="image-20240224113754298"></p><p><strong>Logging Service</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224113825213.png" alt="image-20240224113825213"></p><p><strong>SNS &amp; SQS</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224114355565.png" alt="image-20240224114355565"></p><p><strong>SNS &amp; SES</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224114622117.png" alt="image-20240224114622117"></p><p>Artifact -&gt; 权威的安全认证</p><p>Inspector -&gt; 生成EC2的安全报告文件</p><p><strong>Inspector &amp; Trusted Advisor</strong></p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224114918056.png" alt="image-20240224114918056"></p><p><strong>AWS Security Hub</strong></p><p>AWS Security Hub is a cloud security posture management service that performs automated, continuous security best practice checks against your AWS resources. Security Hub aggregates your security alerts (i.e. findings) from various AWS services and partner products in a standardized format so that you can more easily take action on them.</p><p><strong>AWS Config</strong></p><p>AWS Config is a fully managed service that provides you with an AWS resource inventory, configuration history, and configuration change notifications to enable security and governance. The AWS Config Rules feature enables you to create rules that automatically check the configuration of AWS resources recorded by AWS Config.</p><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240224160815040.png" alt="image-20240224160815040"></p><p>ECS 托管的容器服务，没有全部控制权</p><p>EC2 有full control</p><hr><p>Which AWS service or feature allows a user to establish a dedicated network connection between a company’s on-premises data center and the AWS Cloud?</p><ul><li><strong>A. AWS Direct Connect</strong></li><li>B. VPC peering</li><li>C. AWS VPN</li><li>D. Amazon Route 53</li></ul><p>AWS Direct Connect establish a dedicated network connection </p><p>AWS VPN provides a secure, encrypted connection between on-premises networks and AWS VPCs <strong>over the internet</strong></p><hr><p>A company wants to protect its AWS Cloud information, systems, and assets while performing risk assessment and mitigation tasks.<br>Which pillar of the AWS Well-Architected Framework is supported by these goals?</p><ul><li>A. Reliability</li><li><strong>B. Security</strong></li><li>C. Operational excellence</li><li>D. Performance efficiency</li></ul><p>Operational Excellence: Focuses on operational practices that enable efficient management and operation of systems. It involves continuous improvement, monitoring, incident response, and evolving procedures over time.</p><p>Security: Focuses on protecting information, systems, and assets. It involves implementing best practices for identity and access management, data protection, and risk assessment and mitigation.</p><p>Reliability: Focuses on the ability of a system to recover from failures and meet customer expectations. It involves implementing best practices for resiliency, fault tolerance, and disaster recovery.</p><p>Performance Efficiency: Focuses on using resources efficiently to maintain good performance. It involves optimizing workloads, selecting the right resources, and monitoring performance.</p><p>Cost Optimization: Focuses on avoiding unnecessary costs and ensuring that resources are used efficiently. It involves optimizing costs, understanding pricing models, and using resources effectively.</p><hr><p>A company needs to block SQL injection attacks.<br>Which AWS service or feature can meet this requirement?</p><ul><li><strong>A. AWS WAF</strong></li><li>B. AWS Shield</li><li>C. Network ACLs</li><li>D. Security groups</li></ul><p>A. AWS WAF (Web Application Firewall): A web application firewall that allows users to create custom rules to filter and monitor HTTP or HTTPS requests to a web application. It helps protect against common web exploits, including SQL injection attacks, by allowing the blocking or rate-limiting of malicious requests. </p><p>各种网络层攻击</p><p>B. AWS Shield: A managed Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) protection service. While it helps protect against DDoS attacks, it is not specifically designed for blocking SQL injection attacks.</p><p>主要是DDoS</p><hr><p>Which AWS service gives users the ability to discover and protect sensitive data that is stored in Amazon S3 buckets?</p><ul><li>A. Amazon Macie</li><li>B. Amazon Detective</li><li>C. Amazon GuardDuty</li><li>D. AWS IAM Access Analyzer</li></ul><p>Amazon Macie: A security service that uses machine learning to automatically discover, classify, and protect sensitive data, such as personally identifiable information (PII), in Amazon S3.</p><p>Amazon Detective: A security service that helps users investigate and identify the root cause of potential security issues or suspicious activities.</p><p>Amazon GuardDuty: A threat detection service that continuously monitors for malicious activity and unauthorized behavior to protect AWS accounts and workloads.</p><p>AWS IAM Access Analyzer: Helps users identify resources that can be accessed by external principals (such as IAM roles or resource-based policies) and provides findings to help ensure resources are shared securely.</p><h2 id="Advantages-of-Cloud-Compute"><a href="#Advantages-of-Cloud-Compute" class="headerlink" title="Advantages of Cloud Compute"></a>Advantages of Cloud Compute</h2><ul><li><strong>Trade fixed expense for variable expense</strong> – Instead of having to invest heavily in data centers and servers before you know how you’re going to use them, you can pay only when you consume computing resources, and pay only for how much you consume.</li><li><strong>Benefit from massive economies of scale</strong> – By using cloud computing, you can achieve a lower variable cost than you can get on your own. Because usage from hundreds of thousands of customers is aggregated in the cloud, providers such as AWS can achieve higher economies of scale, which translates into lower pay as-you-go prices.</li><li><strong>Stop guessing capacity</strong> – Eliminate guessing on your infrastructure capacity needs. When you make a capacity decision prior to deploying an application, you often end up either sitting on expensive idle resources or dealing with limited capacity. With cloud computing, these problems go away. You can access as much or as little capacity as you need, and scale up and down as required with only a few minutes’ notice.</li><li><strong>Increase speed and agility</strong> – In a cloud computing environment, new IT resources are only a click away, which means that you reduce the time to make those resources available to your developers from weeks to just minutes. This results in a dramatic increase in agility for the organization, since the cost and time it takes to experiment and develop is significantly lower.</li><li><strong>Stop spending money running and maintaining data centers</strong> – Focus on projects that differentiate your business, not the infrastructure. Cloud computing lets you focus on your own customers, rather than on the heavy lifting of racking, stacking, and powering servers.</li><li><strong>Go global in minutes</strong> – Easily deploy your application in multiple regions around the world with just a few clicks. This means you can provide lower latency and a better experience for your customers at minimal cost.</li></ul><h2 id="AWS-Well-Architected-Framework"><a href="#AWS-Well-Architected-Framework" class="headerlink" title="AWS Well-Architected Framework"></a>AWS Well-Architected Framework</h2><h3 id="Six-pillars-of-the-framework"><a href="#Six-pillars-of-the-framework" class="headerlink" title="Six pillars of the framework"></a>Six pillars of the framework</h3><ul><li><strong>operational excellence</strong></li><li><strong>security</strong></li><li><strong>reliability</strong></li><li><strong>performance efficiency</strong></li><li><strong>cost optimization</strong></li><li><strong>sustainability</strong></li></ul><h3 id="Operational-excellence"><a href="#Operational-excellence" class="headerlink" title="Operational excellence"></a>Operational excellence</h3><p>The Operational Excellence pillar includes the ability to support development and run workloads effectively, gain insight into their operations, and to continuously improve supporting processes and procedures to deliver business value.</p><h3 id="Security"><a href="#Security" class="headerlink" title="Security"></a>Security</h3><p>The Security pillar encompasses the ability to protect data, systems, and assets to take advantage of cloud technologies to improve your security.</p><h3 id="Reliability"><a href="#Reliability" class="headerlink" title="Reliability"></a>Reliability</h3><p>The Reliability pillar encompasses the ability of a workload to perform its intended function correctly and consistently when it’s expected to. This includes the ability to operate and test the workload through its total lifecycle. This paper provides in-depth, best practice guidance for implementing reliable workloads on AWS.</p><h3 id="Performance-efficiency"><a href="#Performance-efficiency" class="headerlink" title="Performance efficiency"></a>Performance efficiency</h3><p>The Performance Efficiency pillar includes the ability to use computing resources efficiently to meet system requirements, and to maintain that efficiency as demand changes and technologies evolve.</p><h3 id="Cost-optimization"><a href="#Cost-optimization" class="headerlink" title="Cost optimization"></a>Cost optimization</h3><p>The Cost Optimization pillar includes the ability to run systems to deliver business value at the lowest price point.</p><h3 id="Sustainability"><a href="#Sustainability" class="headerlink" title="Sustainability"></a>Sustainability</h3><p>The Sustainability pillar focuses on environmental impacts, especially energy consumption and efficiency, since they are important levers for architects to inform direct action to reduce resource usage.</p><h2 id="AWS-Cloud-Adoption-Framework-AWS-CAF"><a href="#AWS-Cloud-Adoption-Framework-AWS-CAF" class="headerlink" title="AWS Cloud Adoption Framework (AWS CAF)"></a>AWS Cloud Adoption Framework (AWS CAF)</h2><ul><li><strong>业务视角</strong>有助于确保您的云投资能够加快实现数字化转型雄心和业务成果。常见的利益攸关方包括首席执行官 (CEO)、首席财务官 (CFO)、首席运营官 (COO)、首席信息官 (CIO) 和首席技术官 (CTO)。</li><li><strong>人员视角</strong>充当了技术与业务之间的桥梁，可加速云之旅以帮助企业更快地打造持续增长和学习的文化，使变革成为业务常态，并将重点放在文化、组织结构、领导力和劳动力上。常见的利益攸关方包括 CIO、COO、CTO、云主管以及跨职能部门和企业内的领导者。</li><li><strong>治理视角</strong>可帮助您协调云计划，最大限度地提高组织收益并最大限度地降低与转型相关的风险。常见的利益攸关方包括首席转型官、CIO、CTO、CFO、首席数据官 (CDO) 和首席风险官 (CRO)。</li><li><strong>平台视角</strong>可帮助您构建企业级、可扩展的混合云平台，实现现有工作负载的现代化，并实施新的云原生解决方案。常见的利益攸关方包括 CTO、技术负责人、架构师和工程师。</li><li><strong>安全视角</strong>可帮助您实现数据和云工作负载的机密性、完整性和可用性。常见的利益攸关方包括首席信息安全干事 (CISO)、首席合规官 (CCO)、内部审计主管以及安全架构师和工程师。</li><li><strong>运营视角</strong>有助于确保云服务的交付水平能够满足您的业务需求。常见的利益攸关方包括基础设施和运营负责人、站点可靠性工程师和信息技术服务经理。</li></ul><h2 id="Managed-service"><a href="#Managed-service" class="headerlink" title="Managed service"></a>Managed service</h2><p>Amazon RDS、Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS)、Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS)、 Amazon DynamoDB …</p><h2 id="Security-1"><a href="#Security-1" class="headerlink" title="Security"></a>Security</h2><h3 id="Identity-and-Access-Management-IAM"><a href="#Identity-and-Access-Management-IAM" class="headerlink" title="Identity and Access Management(IAM)"></a>Identity and Access Management(IAM)</h3><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240220205055568.png" alt="image-20240220205055568"></p><h3 id="AWS-Artifact"><a href="#AWS-Artifact" class="headerlink" title="AWS Artifact"></a>AWS Artifact</h3><p>AWS Artifact is your go-to, central resource for compliance-related information that matters to you. It provides on-demand access to AWS security and compliance reports and select online agreements. </p><p>（合规性）</p><h3 id="Detect-Protect"><a href="#Detect-Protect" class="headerlink" title="Detect &amp; Protect"></a>Detect &amp; Protect</h3><h4 id="Amazon-Inspector"><a href="#Amazon-Inspector" class="headerlink" title="Amazon Inspector"></a>Amazon Inspector</h4><p>Amazon Inspector is a new automated vulnerability management service that continually scans AWS workloads for software vulnerabilities and unintended network exposure.</p><h4 id="Amazon-GuardDuty"><a href="#Amazon-GuardDuty" class="headerlink" title="Amazon GuardDuty"></a>Amazon GuardDuty</h4><p>Amazon GuardDuty is a threat detection service that continuously monitors for malicious activity and anomalous behavior to protect your AWS accounts, workloads, Kubernetes clusters, and data stored in Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3).</p><h4 id="Amazon-Macie"><a href="#Amazon-Macie" class="headerlink" title="Amazon Macie"></a>Amazon Macie</h4><p>Amazon Macie is a fully managed <strong>data security and data privacy service</strong> that uses inventory evaluations, machine learning, and pattern matching to discover sensitive data and accessibility in your Amazon S3 environment.</p><h4 id="Amazon-Detective"><a href="#Amazon-Detective" class="headerlink" title="Amazon Detective"></a>Amazon Detective</h4><p>Amazon Detective makes it easy to <em>analyze, investigate, and quickly identify</em> the root cause of potential security issues or suspicious activities.</p><h4 id="AWS-Shield"><a href="#AWS-Shield" class="headerlink" title="AWS Shield"></a>AWS Shield</h4><p>AWS Shield is a managed <strong>Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) protection service</strong> that safeguards web applications running on AWS. AWS Shield provides you with always-on detection and automatic inline mitigations that minimize application downtime and latency</p><blockquote><p>Standard version Work on network &amp; transport layer</p><p>Advanced version include AWS WAF</p></blockquote><h4 id="AWS-WAF"><a href="#AWS-WAF" class="headerlink" title="AWS WAF"></a>AWS WAF</h4><p>AWS WAF is a web application ﬁrewall that helps protect your web applications or APIs against common web exploits and bots that may affect availability, compromise security, or consume excessive resources. AWS WAF gives you control over how traffic reaches your applications by enabling you to create security rules that control bot traffic and block common attack patterns, such as <em>SQL injection or cross-site scripting.</em></p><blockquote><p>Work on application layer</p></blockquote><h4 id="AWS-Security-Hub"><a href="#AWS-Security-Hub" class="headerlink" title="AWS Security Hub"></a>AWS Security Hub</h4><p>AWS Security Hub is a cloud security posture management service that performs automated, continuous security best practice checks against your AWS resources.</p><ul><li><strong>threat detections -&gt; <em>GuardDuty</em></strong></li><li><strong>vulnerabilities -&gt; <em>Amazon Inspector</em></strong></li><li><strong>sensitive data classifications -&gt; <em>Amazon Macie</em></strong></li><li><strong>resource configuration issues -&gt; <em>AWS Config</em></strong></li><li><strong>DDoS -&gt; <em>AWS Shield</em></strong></li><li><strong>SQL injection… -&gt; <em>AWS WAF</em></strong></li><li>AWS Partner Network products.</li></ul><h3 id="Key-Access"><a href="#Key-Access" class="headerlink" title="Key &amp; Access"></a>Key &amp; Access</h3><h4 id="AWS-Secrets-Manager"><a href="#AWS-Secrets-Manager" class="headerlink" title="AWS Secrets Manager"></a>AWS Secrets Manager</h4><p>AWS Secrets Manager helps you protect secrets needed to access your applications, services, and IT resources. The service enables you to easily <em>rotate, manage, and retrieve</em> <strong>database credentials, API keys, and other secrets</strong> throughout their lifecycle.</p><h4 id="AWS-Key-Management-Service"><a href="#AWS-Key-Management-Service" class="headerlink" title="AWS Key Management Service"></a>AWS Key Management Service</h4><p>AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS) makes it easy for you to create and manage cryptographic keys and control their use across a wide range of AWS services and in your applications.</p><blockquote><p>Create and control keys used to <em><strong>encrypt or digitally sign the data</strong></em> </p></blockquote><h2 id="AWS-Global-Infrastructure"><a href="#AWS-Global-Infrastructure" class="headerlink" title="AWS Global Infrastructure"></a>AWS Global Infrastructure</h2><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240226225248261.png" alt="image-20240226225248261"></p><h2 id="Management"><a href="#Management" class="headerlink" title="Management"></a>Management</h2><h3 id="Access"><a href="#Access" class="headerlink" title="Access"></a>Access</h3><ul><li>Programming access (API, CLI, SDK)</li><li>AWS Management Console</li><li>Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</li></ul><h3 id="Network"><a href="#Network" class="headerlink" title="Network"></a>Network</h3><p><img src="/img/AWS%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%AC%94%E8%AE%B0/image-20240225230919540.png" alt="image-20240225230919540"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>AWS</tag>
      
      <tag>Cloud</tag>
      
      <tag>Certification</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>AWS Basic</title>
    <link href="/2024/04/29/AWS-Basic/"/>
    <url>/2024/04/29/AWS-Basic/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Cloud-Computing"><a href="#Cloud-Computing" class="headerlink" title="Cloud Computing ?"></a>Cloud Computing ?</h2><p>Cloud computing is the on-demand delivery of compute power, database, storage, applications, and other IT resources through a cloud services platform via the internet with pay-as-you-go pricing.</p><p>Cloud computing provides a simple way to access servers, storage, databases and a broad set of application services over the internet.</p><h3 id="Advantages"><a href="#Advantages" class="headerlink" title="Advantages"></a><strong>Advantages</strong></h3><ul><li><strong>Trade fixed expense for variable expense</strong></li><li><strong>Benefit from massive economies of scale</strong></li><li><strong>Stop guessing capacity</strong> </li><li><strong>Increase speed and agility</strong></li><li><strong>Stop spending money running and maintaining data centers</strong> </li><li><strong>Go global in minutes</strong></li></ul><h2 id="AWS-Global-Infrastructure"><a href="#AWS-Global-Infrastructure" class="headerlink" title="AWS Global Infrastructure"></a>AWS Global Infrastructure</h2><p>The AWS Cloud infrastructure is built around <strong>AWS Regions</strong> and <strong>Availability Zones</strong>. </p><p>An AWS Region is a physical location in the world which has multiple Availability Zones.</p><p>Availability Zones consist of one or more discrete data centers, each with redundant power, networking, and connectivity, housed in separate facilities. These Availability Zones offer you the ability to operate production applications and databases that are more highly available, fault tolerant, and scalable than would be possible from a single data center.</p><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240219160453628.png" alt="image-20240219160453628"></p><h3 id="AWS-Region-considerations"><a href="#AWS-Region-considerations" class="headerlink" title="AWS Region considerations"></a>AWS Region considerations</h3><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240219161112081.png" alt="image-20240219161112081"></p><h3 id="Maintain-Resiliency"><a href="#Maintain-Resiliency" class="headerlink" title="Maintain Resiliency"></a>Maintain Resiliency</h3><p>To keep the application available, you need to maintain high availability and resiliency. A well-known best practice for cloud architecture is to use Region-scoped, managed services. These services come with availability and resiliency built in. When that is not possible, make sure the workload is replicated across multiple AZs. At a minimum, you should use two AZs. If one entire AZ fails, your application will have infrastructure up and running in at least a second AZ to take over the traffic.</p><h2 id="AWS-Cloud-Security"><a href="#AWS-Cloud-Security" class="headerlink" title="AWS Cloud Security"></a>AWS Cloud Security</h2><p>The AWS Cloud enables a shared responsibility model. While AWS manages security <strong>of</strong> the cloud, you are responsible for security <strong>in</strong> the cloud. This means that you retain control of the security you choose to implement to protect your own content, platform, applications, systems, and networks no differently than you would in an on-site data center.</p><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240219161532026.png" alt="image-20240219161532026"></p><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240219161747050.png" alt="image-20240219161747050"></p><h3 id="Protect-the-AWS-Root-User"><a href="#Protect-the-AWS-Root-User" class="headerlink" title="Protect the AWS Root User"></a>Protect the AWS Root User</h3><h4 id="Authentication"><a href="#Authentication" class="headerlink" title="Authentication?"></a>Authentication?</h4><p>If the user types in the correct email and password, the system assumes the user is allowed to enter and grants them access. This is the process of <em><strong>authentication</strong></em>. Authentication ensures that the user is who they say they are.</p><h4 id="Authorization"><a href="#Authorization" class="headerlink" title="Authorization?"></a>Authorization?</h4><p>Authorization is the process of giving users permission to access AWS resources and services. Authorization determines whether the user can perform an action.</p><h4 id="AWS-Root-User"><a href="#AWS-Root-User" class="headerlink" title="AWS Root User"></a>AWS Root User</h4><p>When you first create an AWS account, you begin with a single sign-in identity that has complete access to all AWS services and resources in the account. This identity is called the AWS root user and is accessed by signing in with the email address and password that you used to create the account.</p><h4 id="Best-Practices"><a href="#Best-Practices" class="headerlink" title="Best Practices"></a>Best Practices</h4><ul><li>Choose a strong password for the root user.</li><li>Never share your root user password or access keys with anyone.</li><li>Disable or delete the access keys associated with the root user.</li><li>Do not use the root user for administrative tasks or everyday tasks.</li><li><em><strong>Use Multi-Factor Authentication(MFA)</strong></em></li></ul><h2 id="AWS-Identity-and-Access-Management-IAM"><a href="#AWS-Identity-and-Access-Management-IAM" class="headerlink" title="AWS Identity and Access Management(IAM)"></a>AWS Identity and Access Management(IAM)</h2><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220204907737.png" alt="image-20240220204907737" style="zoom:50%;" /><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220205055568.png" alt="image-20240220205055568"></p><h3 id="IAM-USER"><a href="#IAM-USER" class="headerlink" title="IAM USER?"></a>IAM USER?</h3><p>An IAM user represents a person or service that interacts with AWS. You define the user within your AWS account. Once you create a user, that user can sign in to gain access to the AWS resources inside your account.</p><h3 id="IAM-GROUP"><a href="#IAM-GROUP" class="headerlink" title="IAM GROUP?"></a>IAM GROUP?</h3><p>An IAM group is a collection of users. All users in the group inherit the permissions assigned to the group. It’s a more convenient and scalable way of managing permissions for users in your AWS account. This is why using IAM groups is a best practice.</p><h3 id="IAM-POLICY"><a href="#IAM-POLICY" class="headerlink" title="IAM POLICY?"></a>IAM POLICY?</h3><p>To manage access and provide permissions to AWS services and resources, you create IAM policies and attach them to IAM users, groups, and roles. </p><h2 id="IAM-ROLES"><a href="#IAM-ROLES" class="headerlink" title="IAM ROLES"></a>IAM ROLES</h2><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220205902662.png" alt="image-20240220205902662"></p><p><strong>FEATURES</strong></p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220210110295.png" alt="image-20240220210110295" style="zoom:67%;" /><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220210205538.png" alt="image-20240220210205538"></p><h3 id="Role-Based-Access-in-AWS"><a href="#Role-Based-Access-in-AWS" class="headerlink" title="Role Based Access in AWS"></a>Role Based Access in AWS</h3><ul><li><p>LOCK DOWN THE AWS ROOT USER</p><ul><li>Don’t share the credentials associated with the root user.</li><li>Consider deleting the root user access keys.</li><li>Enable MFA on the root account.</li></ul></li><li><p>FOLLOW THE PRINCIPLE OF LEAST PRIVILEGE</p></li><li><p>USE <strong>IAM ROLES</strong> WHEN POSSIBLE</p></li><li><p>CONSIDER USING AN IDENTITY PROVIDER(idP)</p></li></ul><h2 id="AWS-Compute"><a href="#AWS-Compute" class="headerlink" title="AWS Compute"></a>AWS Compute</h2><h3 id="Amazon-Elastic-Compute-Cloud"><a href="#Amazon-Elastic-Compute-Cloud" class="headerlink" title="Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud"></a>Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud</h3><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/J8AK7AJ5Rd-CJYWBoshBqg_cb704f22a39746e398bff9b1838c91f1_image.png" alt="img"></p><p>Amazon EC2 is a web service that provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. It allows you to provision virtual servers called EC2 instances. </p><p>When launching an EC2 instance, the first setting you configure is which operating system you want by selecting an Amazon Machine Image (AMI).</p><blockquote><p>In the AWS Cloud, operating system installation is instead built into the AMI that you choose. Not only does an AMI let you configure which operating system you want, you can also select storage mappings, the architecture type, and additional software installed.</p></blockquote><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/VBk76PGITdKLGz9RPTGtXw_16b6431eb1354ab889f7433d964da9f1_image.png" alt="img"></p><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/rGO-wfxDSs6pvOl6I3QaYQ_28d2e58cdf33439bb53d1af93d907cf1_image.png" alt="img"></p><p>you can create an AMI from your running instance and use this AMI to start a new instance. This way, your new instance will have all the same configurations as your current instance, because the configurations set in the AMIs are the same.</p><p><img src="/img/AWS-Basic/image-20240220220310127.png" alt="image-20240220220310127"></p><p>When you <em><strong>stop</strong></em> your instance, the data stored in memory (RAM) is lost.</p><p>When you <em><strong>stop-hibernate</strong></em> your instance, AWS signals the operating system to perform hibernation (suspend-to-disk), which saves the contents from the instance memory (RAM) to the Amazon EBS root volume. </p><h4 id="On-Demand-Instances"><a href="#On-Demand-Instances" class="headerlink" title="On-Demand Instances"></a>On-Demand Instances</h4><p>With <em>On-Demand</em> instances, you pay for compute capacity with no long-term commitments. Billing begins whenever the instance is running, and billing stops when the instance is in a stopped or terminated state. The price per second for a running On-Demand instance is fixed.</p><h4 id="Reserved-Instances-RIs"><a href="#Reserved-Instances-RIs" class="headerlink" title="Reserved Instances (RIs)"></a>Reserved Instances (RIs)</h4><p>RIs provide you with a significant discount compared to On-Demand instance pricing. RIs provide a discounted hourly rate and an optional capacity reservation for EC2 instances.</p><h3 id="Container-Services-on-AWS"><a href="#Container-Services-on-AWS" class="headerlink" title="Container Services on AWS"></a>Container Services on AWS</h3>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>AWS</tag>
      
      <tag>Cloud</tag>
      
      <tag>Certificate</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2024/04/29/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2024/04/29/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
